I know uh Emily just told me Jay isn't
here, but I I wanted to pass along my
condolences to Jay. I miss seeing him
here. Um uh I've been thinking about
him. I've been uh praying for him and I
look forward to seeing him back here
with this group and uh if anybody sees
them, give them my best. But uh I miss
you, Jay.
Um, I'll just say a couple things. Um,
I'm normally not a pad guy writing
things down, but I've got a lot of
thoughts on the season that I'd like to
share. And, uh, I'm sure we'll get to
them as we get to the questions, so it
won't take very long at all. But it it
goes without saying this season is not
what we expect. Certainly not what we
will accept, and everybody here knows
that. Uh, it was frustrating. It was
challenging. It was disappointing for
all of us. But more importantly, it was
all those things for our fans. We feel
that that weighs on us. Uh it it it
hurts us cuz we know that they have high
expectations for us. We embrace those
high expectations. Believe me, we have
high expectations for this football team
as well. We didn't meet those
expectations. the group we put out there
did not fulfill those expectations.
So, it motivates us. It really motivates
us to be better. Uh to put a group out
there that will
make the city proud. Uh that will finish
games. We have a lot of work to do this
off season. We are aware of that. Um
we're motivated for it. Uh we're excited
about it. We have a football team that
uh has some challenges that we've got to
solve, but beyond that, we have a
football team that has a lot of
positives to build on and a lot of
things we're proud of and a lot of
reasons for optimism. So, those are
things that uh that we're excited about.
Um, we just have to this off season it's
going to be all about uh the who's doing
it, the what they're doing and how
they're doing it. That's the focus. I
really believe in the group that we have
here. Why do I believe in them? Because
that they have shown that they can do
it. Uh they're a collaborative group.
They're a smart group. They've been
there before. We have excellent coaches
in my opinion. They're good teachers.
Our players respect them. We have a team
that despite the fact that we were out
of it was still enjoying being around
each other, still working hard, and to
the very end of this season, still
improving. Uh that makes me feel good.
It really does. I I'm proud of that. I'm
proud of the motivation our coaches
provided. I'm proud of the camaraderie
that our team has within it to do that.
and I saw a lot of positives even though
there was very little to play for and
that and that uh does make me feel
better. Uh so I do believe in the people
that we have here. Um you know I I've
been here a long time. I don't take this
job lightly. I don't take it for
granted. Uh it's the only job I've
wanted. It's what I've chosen to do with
my life. This team is part of my fabric.
Um, I wake up with the singular focus of
how to make this team better. It's what
I do. It's a part of who I am in the
city. That is my home. And, uh, it hurts
when uh, we're not representing the city
the way that we need to. I think we're
capable of it. Uh, but we got to find
the solutions to win uh, and produce in
the critical moments of games. The last
two seasons have been derailed by
critical moment execution errors and we
have to find the group of 11 to put out
there that will execute in the critical
moments and I and I believe that we'll
do that. Um but I I'm confident. I I
think there's great days ahead for our
football team. There's a lot of work to
do. We're motivated to do it. We're
excited to be here to do it. I'm excited
to be here. Again, I don't take this for
granted. I work for a fantastic football
team in a wonderful city that's my home
and I'm humbled by that. I really am.
Um, so we have areas of concern. We have
reasons for optimism. And with that, I
will open it up to all of you and
hopefully we'll get to all those good
areas.
>> How do you find those those players,
that 11? What What do you need to do to
make sure that you field that team next
season? Yeah, quite frankly, it's hard
work and and uh we have to find what we
believe we need the most and then find
find the players with those traits uh
that'll fill those needs. And uh it's a
lot of work. We've gone through a week
uh right now of college scouting
meetings and every year, you know, I I
I've told you guys this before. I am so
impressed with our group up there with
the information, background research,
uh, and, uh, and time on task that they
put into analyzing each and every one of
these college football players. And so,
they're long meetings, they're fun
meetings. Uh, there's a lot of players
that we talk about that you can envision
on our football team. And, uh, so that
uh, I think makes everybody feel
positive that there are answers out
there. We've got to make the right
decisions. It's on me to point us in the
right direction. When we've had
failures, I pointed us in the wrong
direction. We are a highly collaborative
football team. We really are. We want
everybody's buy in on what we're doing.
We want them to know the why of what
we're doing. Uh the reasons for the
decision and what the vision for the
individual players that are here is. And
we want everybody on board with that.
But when we get pointed on the wrong
guy, it's me. I have to steer the ship
away from poor decisions even though
it's what we might feel at the time and
I have to do a better job of getting us
pointed at the right decisions at the
critical times. We've done that. We've
had good decisions uh and they're
collaborative decisions, but I've got to
do a better job of weeding out the bad
decisions and we have made some. Uh
every team does, but um we've also made
some good decisions. Do you regret? Do
you regret not signing more external
guys last off season? External?
>> Um, yeah, last off season, uh, it was a
challenging offseason. I think we did a
lot of things that people didn't think
we could do or at least they voiced that
we could not do. Uh, we we attacked last
off season uh in a pretty big way. Uh
again, we we resigned guys that we felt
fit what we were going to do, that we
believed in uh uh being key contributors
for us. And you're talking on defense,
but really with the offseason signings,
I I think we wrote um well over $400
million worth of contracts last off
season. When when you sum up everything
we did, those aren't easy. And uh and
those negotiations aren't easy. Uh but
we were satisfied that we were
maintaining
clear top of the league players. We have
clear elite elite worldclass best in the
world players on this football team.
That's one of the reasons we have high
expectations. We didn't want to lose
that and we wanted that continuity to
build off of. Did we build off of it
enough? Was the defense up to it enough?
Obviously, it wasn't. And that falls on
me. Um, but we we did at the time what
we thought would uh would produce for
us.
>> You said you believe in your staff and
the guys you worked with.
>> Yeah.
>> But three straight non-playoff years,
two in the last 10 is all you made the
playoffs. Why should fans have that
fully thing you need to do?
>> Well, I understand that they probably
don't right now. Uh, all I can do is
work us out of it. Uh we've done it
before, you know, we've done it before
with a team full of draft choices and
had highlevel football teams. We've done
it before with a blend of free agents
and draft choices. And then we've also
taken us to the Super Bowl with a number
of UFA signings. So, we can add to the
team in a lot of different areas. Uh we
have excellent uh scouts who give us the
analysis. It's it's on us to make the
right decisions. Uh, and even if you
want a player, doesn't mean you get
them. It doesn't mean you get them in
the draft. It doesn't mean you get them
in free agency. The whole puzzle does
have to fit together. And so, we work to
fit the puzzle together in the best way
that we can uh that we can do that.
>> You talked earlier about
>> why do you believe you should still be
in the job? And if and then also, what
will you will you look to do anything
differently than you've done previously
in your career? Yeah, I you know if if
your question is do I have confidence in
myself? I do. But most importantly, I've
got confidence in the people here. I I
really do. And I've got confidence in
the processes that we have here. And
I've got confidence in our ownership. Um
I've got confidence in the players we
have. We we have very good players. Um
it's it's not up to me to determine
whether I'm here or not. I've been doing
this my whole life. It is my life. NFL
football has been a part of my life
since I opened my eyes. That is what I
do. So, I believe I know this game. I
believe I know players. And I know for a
fact that nobody works at it more than
me. And it doesn't occupy anybody's mind
more than this occupies my mind. I've
seen it. I've seen it at high levels.
We've had success here. I've seen it
other places. I know what it looks like.
But it's not about me. It's about our
group. And that's what gives me the most
confidence. It's about what I've seen in
our group, not only in the personnel
area, in the coaching area as well, and
in what we have in the locker room right
now.
>> Well, you went as far as to say you
thought you had a championship team
going into this season.
>> Absolutely.
>> Is there
>> We still have a championship team in my
mind. We have elite worldclass players.
We had a lot of challenges this this
year. A lot of challenges. We didn't
navigate them effectively enough. We
navigated some of them as effectively as
you could and then we had challenges
elsewhere. Uh when you lose your
quarterback, we've we have a quarterback
that we have taken great pains in
building an offense around and for. And
it does. and that offense took steps
this year without him. And so with him,
we feel like that is starting to just
hit its stride with the way the
offensive line came on, when the way
with the way the running game came on.
Uh I I would tell you that I saw things
this year that I wouldn't have thought I
would ever see. uh somebody walk into
the building two days before a game,
pick up an incredibly complex offense,
go out with people he just shook hands
with, and make it work. That is amazing.
You know, you know people from afar
because they're in the same industry as
you. And I know Joe Flacco from afar,
but when you meet him and get to
appreciate what he's all about and what
he accomplished here in such a short
time, and then go out and have an
injury, not be able to practice, and
still go out and produce. That speaks to
to him. It uh it also speaks to our
coaches and how they are able to
immediately pivot and regenerate
something that gave us a chance. Other
parts of the team then decided it wasn't
going to give us a chance. And uh and
that's on me. That's on me. But there
are things that worked and things that
show me, hey, we've got the right people
in this building because that doesn't
happen. That is a rare rare thing that
you can create something out of nothing
and then have the success that that that
had. And uh so I I'm I'm proud of that.
I I really am.
>> Speaking of Joe Burrow, dude, he's
obvious he was obviously disillusioned,
disheartened by the way the season
turned out, what he came back to. I'm
curious what kind of assurances you've
given him that this won't happen again
and that the roster will be competitive
especially on the defensive side where
all the fail where most of the fail
>> we had failure early. The thing that I
saw in our defense though as it went on
Frags is that uh is is that it started
to find its footing. We played a lot of
young guys it started the game slowed
down for them. They sped up. We uh we
finally figured out how to stop the run.
and we were stopping the run. We we were
generating turnovers. When the defense
played well, then it was the offensive
turn to not play well. We have to find
that complimentary football. Um I'm
always open and honest with Joe, you
know, but it takes a full football team
and and I don't believe that that one
side of the ball was was not complicit
in our season. Both sides of the ball,
all three phases were complicit in our
season. and we've got to clean that up.
It's the critical moments of games when
one side is doing well, the other side
has to take advantage. The the main
example of that was Miami. We went down
there, we generated turnovers, we scored
touchdowns. We generated turnover, we
scored touchdown. It's complimentary
football. We didn't have that a lot this
year. We need to find that.
>> You talked earlier.
>> Fans fans are, you know, fans are upset.
I'm here kind of representing fans. I'm
not a sports group.
>> Yeah. They want to know a few things.
What are you going to specifically do in
the offseason to create a championship
team immediately? Will you beef up your
scouting department, which you are very
proud of, but will you beef it up to be
more in line with other NFL teams? And
will you insist on a an offensive play
caller because they're ticket prices are
going up. They're looking at mediocrity
and they need some assurance that some
of these things are going to be
addressed.
What was the second part of that?
Offensive play calling.
>> Offensive play caller. They like they
want your scouting department beefed up
and they want to know like what other
issues, what other things internally,
>> the specifics of the offseason. We're
still going through that right now.
We're still debriefing the season. We're
still analyzing each and every player on
our on our roster where the needs are.
We we have a good feeling for where that
is. I wouldn't outline exactly. We're
going to bring in, you know, Paul over
here and he's going to play, you know,
three technique for us. Uh, we have a
very good idea of of where the needs are
on our football team and we're going to
attack them from a personnel standpoint.
Our coaches during the season did a
great job in what we were asking the
players to do. they made uh changes in
in in how we were going about it and it
worked on that side of on the defensive
side of the ball and honestly it worked
on the offensive side of the ball. So we
had some nimleness during the season.
Um, in terms of our scouting staff, uh,
our scouting staff in in my opinion is
it it is the size that it is because I
think the collaboration
is better at that size. We have never
lacked for information on a player.
There's never been a player selected
that we didn't know anything about.
that we didn't have multiple reports and
large background on. It's not about the
volume of information we have. If we
make a mistake, it's because at the
decision point, we made the wrong
decision, but it wasn't because we
didn't have information on the player.
We have information and we have plenty
of opinion on the player, you know, and
we've made a lot of good picks. I I I I
get that people are don't believe we've
made any good picks. We've made a lot of
good picks on our current roster, on
past rosters, and there will be more on
future rosters. I really believe that.
In terms of our process, every year it
changes some. Every year it evolves. We
have different data sources. Uh we have
uh uh different touch points with the
players. Uh we change our meeting
styles. We change our medicals. We we
involve and change in how we operate.
Every team does. And we also will
involve and change in how we meet and
and when we start attacking free agency
and when we start really making the plan
for the off season. You know, the ra the
NFL season isn't even over yet. Uh but
we're on track with
coming up with our plan for how we will
attack and who might fit the needs that
we'll have. That's something that we're
going through. when you end your season
uh early, it uh it does provide that
benefit that you get on this stuff
earlier.
>> Going into I know you know how rare Joe
Burrow is at quarterback is the past
three seasons the end result. Does it
feel like you're wasting his
championship window, Jamar's
championship window?
>> Well, it's the Bengals and uh and when
we don't win a championship, that's the
only thing that I'm after is a
championship. It's not it's not any
individuals in this building's
championship. It's the Cincinnati
Bengals championship. And that's really
the only definition of success that that
I have. I don't have a definition of
success of making the playoffs or doing
X, Y, or Z. It's the It's the team that
has uh the positive feeling at the end
of the season. That's the only thing
that I'm chasing. That's what we want.
Uh we want it for all of our players.
Uh, we want it for all of our staff. Um,
you know, we we have set our team up for
Joe in a way that we feel is pretty darn
good. And uh and
there are resources on the team that
we've expended on that. So, when you
spend 60% or 65% or whatever it is on
offense of your cap, it's going to
affect the other parts of your team. We
know that we have to find solutions that
fit into that that then produce on the
other side of the ball and we will we're
positive about that.
>> With you saying it's set up well in that
case, what's been the shortcoming over
the last few years in terms of why it
hasn't clicked when you've had
>> well offense has, you know, when Joe's
been in there and when the other Joe's
been in there, it has. That's where the
resources are. Um uh when he's not in
there, it affects the football team. We
we went through a stretch of really good
teams without without him playing. We
started the year 2 and 0. Uh the defense
was was we thought coming along a little
bit, making enough happen for for us to
be a successful team and we lost Joe and
uh it was a tough stretch there for us
until we got rebooted and then we did
get rebooted. But those were good
football teams we play. We play we play
teams with elite talent every week and
uh and we feel like we create problems
for teams. Every team creates problems
in different ways for teams. We feel
like we create problems for teams. You
have to you have to win otherwise you
wouldn't be sitting there asking that
question. We have to win and and we're
keenly aware of that and Joe is a part
of that formula. Well, other teams have
been able to navigate they're losing
their quarterback and still make the
playoffs. What's something what's what's
kind of been the disconnect that hasn't
been able enable you all to kind of
navigate that when Joe goes down to
still have a team good enough to get
into the postseason?
>> Yeah, you know, that's obviously the
goal. That's obviously the goal. Uh it's
a team sport. It's not just a oneperson
sport. And when one person goes down,
you have to have a team that can absorb
it. And uh that's motivating for us to
uh to get to that point where we can do
that
>> without like you said earlier, you know,
talking about exact players that you're
going to be looking for
>> when you look at this team and and this
defense specifically,
>> what kind of traits do you think it
needs? What kind of, you know, makeup do
you think you need to look at to bring
into this group for next year?
>> Yeah, successful defenses, in my
opinion, they they have to be able to
pressure the passer. You'd like to be
able to pressure with four. Um, I think
we need uh we we need pass rush. Um,
I think that relieves some of the strain
on the coverage. So, I I'm a guy that
believes in the front on both sides of
the ball. That I that is my focus.
People might not believe that, but that
is my focus. They might believe I love
throwing the ball down the field and
having great wide outs. Those
opportunities presented themselves. We
grabbed them and we're glad we did. But
I want to build the front. I always want
to build the front. And so there are a
number of pieces that we think we we
need and uh and can add. We'll see if we
can.
>> You mentioned the percentages on offense
versus defense just contractually. Do
you think the organization is willing to
from a contract structure standpoint do
what it takes to get enough on the
defensive side of the ball?
>> I think the organization is willing to
do anything it takes to win. I mean,
that's been my I've been here long
enough to know that. If that wasn't the
case, I wouldn't say it. You know, the
organization wants to win. Mr. Brown
wants to win. Katie, Troy, Elizabeth,
Caroline, Paul, they they want to win.
That's what they want. They're willing
to do whatever it takes. Can
>> Can I just ask a few Thank you for doing
this, by the way.
>> Yeah. You didn't want to come to Mobile,
huh? [laughter]
Um,
>> who has full control of the 53man roster
in this current dynamic that you guys
have in the front office?
>> I don't know that we've ever defined
that to to any degree. We always come to
a collaborative approach.
You know, ultimately this is this is Mr.
grounds team and uh and he's the owner
and if if he or somebody in the
ownership group wants to step in, but it
never happens, doesn't need to happen,
we find the solutions together. Uh Zach
and I will uh we'll we'll hash out.
We'll we'll visit with uh with Katie and
Troy and Mike and uh and we'll come up
with what we feel is best.
>> It's uh it's never been a power thing.
It's it's not like uh I I've never
understood the uh when you have a
collaborative approach like this there
there isn't really a need for anybody to
be thumping anybody else. Um it's my job
to come up with the collaborative
approach, come up with a consensus and
make the decision if that's what you're
asking. But that is not that is not
something that comes into any of our
decisions. as well. It's my decision, so
tough luck. That that doesn't that
doesn't show up.
>> I just I have two more for you. Um I
know you've talked about the growth that
you've seen on defense and and the
complimentary piece of it that you were
missing as a team this year and how
defense played in those first two weeks,
but for two years now, statistically
when you look at the whole year,
>> obviously this year, yeah, 30
[clears throat] and last year I think 25
>> dug a big hole. We dug a big hole. It's
hard to get out of a big hole and and we
dug a big hole.
>> What do you feel like you're missing
most? I know each year is different, but
when you look at what you're missing,
>> depends on the part of the season that
you talk about. Even this year within
this own season, it was it was
different. We we we really struggled to
stop the run and that opened up
everything, you know, else in an
offense. We played good offenses. It's
not an excuse. We also, you know, had to
play large stretches without our high we
actually it was the highest paid guy on
both sides of the ball.
[laughter and gasps] That
wasn't out there for us and and you need
your closers and you need your aces when
it when it comes down to the fourth
quarter and you need a stop. Um but
yeah, and stopping the run. I was proud
of the group [clears throat]
after the buy for figuring out, grinding
through and and making the improvements
necessary to give us give us chances. It
would be a different story if I didn't
see young players progressing
and I didn't see a progression of
understanding, knowledge, and execution
of our defense. It would be a different
story. Believe me, it would be a big
different story in my mind. Uh but the
reason that it's not is because I see
growth. I see growth in a 24 year old
Miles Murphy and and you know
[clears throat] uh young corners who who
have taken the jump and Jordan Battle
who have taken the jump. The one thing
we really need is we need those guys or
somebody else to take on a leadership
role and demand the accountability and
demand the execution. We need more
leadership. We have tons of leadership
on the offensive side of the ball. We
need somebody's
multiple people to step up and and lead
that group from within our team. And it
could come from the outside and it could
come from with with uh from the inside.
We can get improvement from both of
those areas. We can get improvement in
play from the inside which I see
happening and we can get improvement
from the outside be it the draft or free
agency or however we we want to attack
it
>> in the collaborative approach you talked
about
>> if all the different voices are saying
all different players and um is it then
your voice that comes in and says we're
taking Amarius Mims with first round
pick as example. Yeah, it never it never
gets
>> that guy.
>> It never gets to that because the
conversations are never that haphazard.
The conversations are directed, focused,
um more along the lines of of these
three players and how do they fit and
what's your vision for them and does
that match my vision and does that match
Zach's vision and um and and so they're
focused conversations. They're not h it
it's not everybody walking in with any
idea that they ever thought of the night
before. It's it's focused conversations
and and we come to a collaborative
judgment on what is the best way to go.
>> Has it ever come down to that? Like two,
you know, two guys that are being
considered and it comes down to
basically you say
>> Sure. It's it's it's my job to say this
one, not that one. Uh but it it does we
we we work it out. I mean, we work it
out and get everybody on board. When we
make a wrong pick, it's because I let it
get out of out of whack.
>> Just to clarify from earlier, there is
no plan as of right now to expand the
scouting department this off seasonason.
Is that correct?
>> This off season, no, we're we're right
into it right now. There's a lot of work
that's been done. Our our guys are
great. We have fantastic scouts. They
work in every area. Uh they are well
known around college football, around
pro football uh and they give us what we
need. And
>> your man Duke there there's so much
concern about you know Joe Burrow and
his happiness or unhappiness, his unrest
from outside the building. How much do
you allow his voice to carry weights and
offseason decisions and sometimes based
on whether or not he feels like it's
going well or not going well?
>> Well, I I enjoy talking to Joe. You
know, I'm open to to visit with any
player and I have visited with multiple
players over the course of the season
and and I always visit with Joe and does
his opinion matter? Yes, it matters to
me. It does matter to me. Uh he's part
of the collaboration. You know, uh
quarterbacks are that way, particularly
ones at at his level and particularly
ones with his intellect and what he has
to offer. He's got a pulse of our team
and I want to hear that. And so I enjoy
talking to him. I enjoy hearing his
opinions. Uh, in terms of, you know,
when we were in LA at the Super Bowl,
everyone was happy. Guess who else
wasn't happy this year? Me. I wasn't
happy.
Nobody's happy when it's not going well.
Um, you know, I think Zach mentioned it.
It's Paul Brown's famous quote, "Winning
makes believers of us all." Winning
makes believers of us all. We want to
get back to the happiness we had out in
LA at the Super Bowl and and we feel
like we can,
>> but we're not there yet.
>> To follow up on what Jeremy, does that
include potential guaranteed money in
year two or year three for potential
free agents if
>> you're wanting contract specifics on
what we're going to do in the It depends
on the player. It It depends on the
player and what's required.
>> Like I said, you know, we'll do what's
required if we have to, you know, to
secure a player that we think can help
us win. He was asking about Joe and his
happiness. Um, you you mentioned there's
been growth defensively, seeing players
grow, but I think there's concern, Duke,
about the timeline of how long it takes
for players to progress in growth and
then meet the window, right, of Joe
Burrow, Jamar Chase, and T. Higgins.
>> We saw the difference that free agents
can make in 2021 when you supplemented
the defense with readymade difference
makers. Mhm.
>> When you talk about philosophy of the
offseason, you have this window, you
have these pieces. Will you attack free
agency differently knowing how it paid
off in 2021 and knowing that this
defense needs ready?
>> It can definitely work that way. It can
definitely work. We we we are these are
conversations we have. Uh how it works
out it there's not 25 guys you could
sign. There's 31 teams all looking at
the same guys. You got to identify the
right ones, then get them done. And
you're talking about, you know, BJ Hill
and Larry Ojobi and and Trey
Hendrickson, the all guys brought in by
our scouting department, you know, all
guys identified by our scouting
department, recommended by our scouting
department, and all worked out well. Can
that happen? Yes, it it could happen. We
got to find the right guys. They got to
be available to us. They got to be open
to coming to Cincinnati and we've got to
work [clears throat] out the contract.
Those are all ifs. We're not there yet.
We're not sure who's available. What are
what the options are? But yes, we're
open to improving our football team in
any way that we can.
>> You mentioned how good that 21 class
was. Why kind of why haven't y'all hit
in the same way in free a financial
constraints still in some in some of the
the spend areas where you can spend why
haven't you been able to
>> you you again year over year you can't
build your team in free agency it's just
not a sustainable process you have to
have your young guys come on you have to
and whether it's a one-year progression
two-year progression three-year
progression those guys have to come on
if they don't come on that's my fault
we've taken the wrong guys. You know,
we're no longer drafting guys for second
contracts and so forth. We need guys
that come in and can give us some help
right away and then grow into bigger
roles quickly. We need that. That's what
every team needs. And every team has A
players, B players, and C players. And
you need your C players to be able to
fill those roles effectively enough so
your A and B players can have success.
And we've got to do a a better job in
all three of those levels on defense.
And that is something that we're focused
on. We have to get better on all those
levels. But not everybody is going to be
an A player. You can't A, there's not
that many of them out there. And B, you
can't afford them all.
>> Last [clears throat] March, you're
working on the T and Jamar contracts.
Did that specifically prevent you from
adding more than one starter on defense
and free agency? Does the fact that you
don't have stuff like that this year
give you more of an opportunity to add
more?
>> Well, we added guys, but we chose to
bring back guys that we knew that wanted
to be here that uh our incoming staff
felt good about their role with us. So,
it's not that we didn't add. They were
just familiar names to everybody.
>> I think what a lot of fans want to see,
Duke, is a change in approach when
things go wrong. when the results aren't
there, they're going to say, "What's the
front office doing to change things to
maybe get different results?" How do you
answer that question?
>> Yeah. You go out and you trade for Joe
Flacco, you know, [laughter]
and you're talking in season.
>> I mean, on defense.
>> Yeah. Just from the outside,
>> there just isn't there wasn't a lot of
options for us in season on defense that
we felt could could help us in a way
that was meaningful.
There's a lot that goes into that. Um,
believe me, we're always looking. We we
are keenly aware of of our issues as
they're happening real time. They are on
our mind. And uh uh you need to have
guys within your structure that can step
up and that's an offseason thing more
than an inseason thing. But you need to
have the guys in your backup roles that
can step up and hold the fort. And you
need to have guys even on your practice
squad that can step up and hold the
fort.
>> Has it been the past couple of years
going into the draft having [snorts]
some clear
>> holes whether it's tackle or linebacker
or how hard does that make the draft?
And is the goal to not be in that
position on April 1?
>> You don't want to be in that position.
That's not the ideal. many teams find
themselves in that position in today's
NFL. Um I can't imagine what the
colleges are going through. I mean you
you have uh your entire team is a free
agent [laughter] and you have 22 holes
and not two or four. Um it's not what we
want. We want we want those
predetermined. We want to know who's on
our team that are going to that's going
to occupy those needs for us. Um you
know this year on offense we feel really
good. We we we feel like that's a unit
that's going to be back uh uh in full
and we feel like it's a unit that was
really hitting its stride and expanding
on the stride that it that it hit. So,
we feel really good about that side of
the ball and we'll see what we can get
done on on defense. It's important for
us to to
address what needs to be addressed.
We're we we don't bury our head in the
sand. We we see what's going on and
we'll try to address it in every way we
can.
>> Do do you sense this is do you sense
this is a make or break year for this
regime big picture
>> for the regime?
>> I don't [laughter]
there's no comfort zone here. There
there isn't a comfort zone any year in
the NFL. You can go to the Super Bowl
and come back and there's no comfort
zone. There shouldn't be a comfort zone
in anything that you do. We have our
antennas up and we are giving [snorts]
everything we have to the process. Um I
don't worry about regimes and and all
that. Um but I but I can tell you that
there is a focus and and urgency. It
exists all the time though in this
league. There's never not a focus and an
urgency. If you get into this business,
you're uh you're on high alert all the
time,
>> every day. Period.
>> When you look at the 12 one score losses
over the last two years, you're on the
sidelines.
>> It irritates me. It really irritates me.
You have to find ways to close games.
And that has been our number one problem
is when it comes time to close the game,
we haven't closed it. And so, how do you
get over that hump? When we take the
field against any team in this league,
we can win. And that team we're playing
knows it. You We don't go out there and
get pummeled. We We are in it and a lot
of times should win it and then don't. I
think that last game against Cleveland
is just a microcosm of of what we've
had. you know, the defense goes out
there and really pitches one of the
finest games you c you could have and
instead the offense gives four point 14
points up and we lose the game. And so,
uh, there there has to be there has to
be some complimentary football in there,
but it's very frustrating that we've
lost so many close games. Incredibly
frustrating. Had we just won our share
of those, not more than our share, we'd
be talking about at least having
opportunities in the playoffs, which is
where we feel we should be. And I know
we haven't shown that, and I'm not
asking anybody else to feel that way,
but within this building, we know we
should be there.
>> How much impact falls at the feet of the
coaching staff and Zach?
>> It falls at all of our feet. Falls at my
feet. It uh it falls at our players
feet. you know, we put a lot of work
into getting, you know, the technique
taught and then the technique isn't
implemented on the last play of the
Chicago game and you end up where you
end up. You know, I it's there there's a
focus and a strain and a finish that we
have to instill. Uh, winning is not easy
and we have to get to the point where
that focus, strain and finish is in our
DNA and our players have to understand
that, you know, and on this snap I'm
playing the right technique, you know,
I'm not doing my own thing. I'm not, you
know, and and we've just had a mistake,
one of 11 or one or two of 11 have
catastrophic results for our win loss
record. It's not an excuse. It's the
reality of what's happened. And can we
get better? Yes. Do I have a solution?
You know, it it it's every part of our
team. You know, it happens on special
teams from time to time. It happened on
offense against Cleveland. Uh it's h
happened on defense against Chicago,
you know. So it's it it is it
frustrating? It's why I opened with it's
frustrating and it's frustrating for our
fans. It's frustrating for us. I hate
that it's frustrating for our fans. We
have to get over that. Every person in
our locker room, on our coaching level,
and in our front office has to
understand that when it comes time to
win a game, you have to believe and you
have to strain and you have to finish.
It's been our biggest problem. I
appreciate you identifying it because
yes, it's very irritating.
>> How far is the level? How far is the
level of talent on this roster right now
as currently constructed from being
enough talent to win a Super Bowl in
your mind?
>> Depends on which side you talk about. I
think we have emerging talent on
defense. I don't think we're there. Um,
but I think we have guys that can grow
into being there. On offense, I I I
would put our talent up against any team
in the league, and it's better than
most. Now, it's got to stay healthy and
produce and not score nine times for for
our opponent. But yes, I would put it up
against any team in the league. So, are
we there? Yes. We feel like we're a
championship caliber team. We're 6 and
11. I'm 6 and 11. How could you feel
that way? You're an idiot. Well, that's
the way I feel.
>> So, last year, like you number of
contentious negotiations in recent years
that have gone on and brought drama and
inflation to some of the prices. Do you
guys feel, especially with this 23 class
you have coming in, a need to be a
little bit more aggressively proactive
in trying to get extension done early to
avoid some of the pitfalls of the drama
that's gone on over [snorts] the years?
>> Yeah. Um,
like to get deals done early if if we
can fit them and and they work. Yeah.
>> Why has it not been able to be done, do
you think? Well, we've done it from time
to time with with players. I don't know
that it's not been able to be done.
You're referencing T and Jamar, you
know. Uh I guess it wasn't done with
with T.
>> Well, Trey was wasn't a young guy and
we' done multiple deals with Trey and uh
that one that one has was contentious,
but there's a lot of contentious deals.
We're not on an island by oursel in in
that kind of stuff. That's just kind of
the way of the world. And uh we have to
place a value on on a player and they're
going to place their own value on
themsel and we've got to come to
something that makes sense for both. You
know, when I uh negotiate with a player
or an agent, I I'm not negotiating
against that player or that agent. I'm
negotiating on behalf of the rest of our
football team. [laughter]
I'm negotiating on behalf of the city of
Cincinnati who wants the best football
team they could have. That's what I'm I
I'm not saying, you know, you deserve
less and it's an isolated
in a cocoon thing. It's I I'm trying to
preserve as much as I can to do
other things on our football team that
will benefit all of us. And so
that's that's how those things become
that way.
>> How clarity in in those negotiations? I
mean, who runs the lead on that? Is that
Katie that's always running the lead?
Does it change by person?
>> It depends. It depends on the player. We
uh we we have uh different different
folks. Some of our personnel people who
are excellent as I've mentioned um they
[snorts] they will run point on some of
that. Uh everything is a collaborative
effort though. we meet on it uh and and
get updates on on where the negotiation
is and and where we should go with it
and what we can put into that and still
do the other things that we want to do.
>> With respect to the coaching staff, um
>> Dan Pitcher is interviewing today in
Cleveland. What do you think makes him
an attractive candidate? And then do you
envision any changes with the staff
coming up? Well, um, Pitch is telling
he's been around here a long time and
he's earned his way up to where he is
for a reason. Um, everybody that meets
Pitch understands immediately that he's
organized and uh and intelligent. Uh, he
communicates incredibly effective. Um,
he has a vision for for what he wants
and he's really valuable and made
himself really valuable over time here.
Um, so if we lose guys, we'll have to
we'll have to back fill and make
changes. Um, but, [snorts]
uh, as we sit here right now, if we
don't, we'll we'll stay with the guys
that we have.
>> I just wanted to get you on the flacko
deal. We haven't talked yet. Uh, what
was the what was the uh, you know, what
was the impetence of that? And, uh, was
there any, you know, trade within the
division? They had never traded with
Cleveland. Was that any kind of a
>> I don't know that that you know we're
we're at a point where we were looking
at all options for our football team. So
you you go through every team uh you put
a list together of possible options. Um
guys, you know there are there are
unrealistic options and then you you
look at the realistic ones. You make the
phone calls, you have the conversations.
uh you see what is possible and uh and
when you get what's possible uh you take
action and and that one became pop
possible for us and uh we had buyin from
everybody within our building uh to to
go forward with it. It was and it was a
good decision. It was uh it was
something that worked out for us. If for
no other reason just to be around Joe
Flacco is cool. I mean, it was really
cool uh watching him operate and work.
Uh I uh I have a an amazing appreciation
and uh understanding for why a guy can
play as long as a guy can play. If
you're Joe Flacco, it's easy.
>> You reference a lot of coaching points
in terms of finishing games, technique,
stuff like that. Yeah.
>> How do you feel Zach is at getting all
of that across?
>> Well, I I watch it every day. I watch
our coaching staff teach those and uh we
can go 95% of the game playing the right
technique and assignment. Uh it's just
at the critical moments we have these
breakdowns and we've got to get that out
of our DNA and everybody in the building
is keenly aware of that.
>> What's the relationship with you and
Zach been like as he's been here now for
seven years?
>> We have a great relationship. We're on
the same page. I've got nothing but high
regard for for Zach. very few people in
the world could have done what he did to
revamp our offense with with a
quarterback that walked in two days.
Zach is uh is is highly intelligent. Uh
he uh wants input. He uh wants uh
collaboration.
Uh he has great ideas. Um, I I've been
from the first time I uh I met him out
in LA uh been highly highly impressed
with him and I remain that way today.
He's uh I think we're we're fortunate to
have him and I look forward to to him
bouncing back. This this hurts his soul
just like it hurts my soul. This is not
what we uh are about and uh and he's on
lock step with me on that.
>> So, how does it work? I really love this
prospector. I really love this this free
agent. The collaboration element of it
with with you and him specifically.
>> How does it work?
>> How does it Yeah.
>> I don't know. Kind of like the
conversation I guess we're having right
now. We just talk it through and uh you
know, what are the elements that you see
in this guy and how will uh how will he
be used here? And you know, here's
[clears throat] the uh here's the the
things that I don't think he can do. Uh
can you get by without that? Um, you
know, here's the examples of it. You
know, we we watch tape as a group and uh
and you know, there's a lot of ways to
to to work the collaboration [snorts]
that brings people on board that might
not be on board.
>> A few minutes ago, [clears throat] you
mentioned a few minutes ago that you
understand that the fans are frustrated.
You're frustrated.
>> Yeah.
>> Do you believe and have you seen this?
You give us an example. Does the family
understand how frustrated, in fact, I
would say teetering on disheartened that
this fan base is at this point?
>> Oh, there's nobody in this building that
doesn't understand that. We feel it. I
mean, we're the same way. We're we're
disheartened, but we're disheartened for
them being disheartened as well. We um
you know, we want to make the city
proud. That's that's what we want to do.
I We have the greatest fans. I mean,
they are passionate. I they understand
football. They really do. Um, you know,
I get uh calls, emails, uh sometimes
texts. I didn't know how that got out,
but uh a lot of thoughts and ideas on
how uh I can improve and uh sometimes
those are appreciated, but it gives me
an appreciation for the fans uh level of
knowledge and and level of thought and
buyin for what we do. That's important.
Not every city has that. I And I'm not
going to name them to call them out, but
there's not every city has that
communitybased
fan driven experience like we have. It's
a very special thing and uh our fans are
very special to us.
>> Last year there were a lot of resignings
and then you've talked a few minutes ago
about the emerging talent on defense.
going into this free agency, you know,
will you be looking to bring back some
of those defensive players that are free
agents or is it kind of a moving in a
new direction trying to find outside
players to come in?
>> Yeah, you know, uh we're going to weigh
all options. I'm not prepared. Even if I
was willing to share exactly what we
were going to do, I I don't know at this
point what we're going to do. We're
still working through all those options.
Um, but
it it it'll be important for us to make
the right decisions. It it'll be very
important for us to make the right
decisions to improve our football team,
particularly improve our defense. Um,
our defensive staff is uh is really
impressive because they know how so we
don't have this, so how do we adjust? So
we don't have this, how do we adjust? So
we don't have this, how do we adjust?
And you saw that as we went through the
season, their ability to adjust
[clears throat] when you don't have
everything you need. And every team does
this, but you have to have guys that are
able to do that and then start to write
the ship. Believe me, if I didn't see us
riding the ship, if I didn't see players
evolving within what we do and playing
faster and uh and and feeling an energy
about them and a desire even though
you're last in the league, there's still
an energy and a camaraderie about what
you're doing in the locker room, on the
practice field, the night before games.
Uh there there was a positivity and a
growth that happened in the midst of
what could have been a nightmare
scenario where everybody's pointing the
finger at everybody else and you go the
other direction. When you're that way,
you're you're going one of two
directions. We went the right direction
and that's a direct reflection on Al's
coaching and his positivity and and
that's what gives me hope that uh that
we'll get this thing figured out. We we
need an increase in talent on that side
of the ball and there's no question
about it. We'll take a look and see uh
how much we can get done.
>> Does the success of the uh Flaco tra
success of the Flaco trade and then you
also thought we talked about the close
losses. Does that set maybe a new
precedent for being more aggressive in
NC trades
moving forward?
>> Um I don't know that we've ever been
opposed to them. They just got to be
right and they're and they're they're
rare when you start counting them up.
the ones that really matter are even
rarer. Um, a lot of times they're uh
they're this nickel for that nickel and
and [clears throat] nothing comes of it
for really either team. Um, we're not so
interested in doing that type of stuff
as much as when there is a need and an
opportunity or an opportunity even
though there's not a need. Those are
things that we we'll we'll look at. We
look at it in the draft. We look at it
at the trade deadline. We we'll look at
it at the offseason. you know, we're
going to look at every option to add to
our football team and sure, you know,
when things work out, maybe it uh gives
you a little more belief that the next
one will.
>> What priority is there uh move on
bringing back DJ Turner and Dax Hill or
at least extending them at this point?
>> Yeah, I think both of them would be guys
that we would what they showed this year
is that that uh they're pretty high
level cover corners. Uh they they have
uh they have the skill set that we
thought they had. Uh they've developed
the way that we thought they would
develop and um I was impressed with Dax
coming off of his knee injury and you
could just see the confidence grow as as
the longer that that got p you know in
his past and and um
uh really proud of the way DJ you know
grew both as a leader and as a and as a
player. Those guys were we're fortunate
to have them and you know those are guys
to build around [snorts] course
to your defense would you say look
pretty accurate or
>> um yeah you know um in terms of
homegrown talent absolutely you know
those are those are guys that um that
should be feeling like they're leaders
and cornerstones
we need more stones
>> Joe Burrow was pretty adamant about he
praised the personnel in
and things of [snorts] that nature, but
he said something's got to change for us
to get back to the playoff team. In your
mind, what what needs to change?
>> Our record, you know, and not to be, you
know, our record. We need to win games
that we should win instead of finding
ways [snorts] to lose games that we
should win. Um, but we change every
offseason. There'll be new faces.
There'll be new players. Uh, there'll be
new uh schematics. Um, our coaches will
spend the whole off season dialing into
what went right, what went wrong, what
can we build on, how can we change in
what we do. Uh, our personnel staff will
spend the entire off season on uh what
went right, what went wrong, what can we
change in who we have. So, we're working
on the who, they'll work on the what.
The players need to work on the how.
That's the technique and the
assignments. And uh that's why it's the
who, the what, and the how. All of that
needs to improve. All three phases need
to improve. And so there'll be changes
through that process. There'll be
changes in the who, what we're doing,
and and how we're getting it
accomplished.
>> But operationally, you still feel like
the way y'all have done things still is
a good blueprint for how to to be
successful again?
>> What which specific way? I mean, the
operation is pretty big. We've got a lot
of things going on, but um you know,
yeah, we're we always are open to
changes in our processes. Um our meeting
cadence always changes every offseason.
Um our focus for what our football team
needs always changes every offseason. Um
how we're going to go about collecting
what we need changes. So, you know,
we're we're a pretty uh pretty flexible
organization in how we do things and and
really who's doing it, too.
>> Over the past couple of years, have you
looked back or find yourself looking
back and saying, "Dang, we should have
kept Jesse. DJ would would look nice out
there right now." Or anything like that
with past
>> Well, the real reality of our our league
is that you can't keep everybody. You
know, we had we got DJ from somebody. Do
you think they still would like to have
them? We got Trey from somebody. Do you
think they would still like to have We
got good players from other team. Every
team gets good players from other teams.
You can't dwell on that. Nor can you
ever keep every good player that you
have. That's just not the nature of this
league. Uh this league is built around
free agency and free agency is a real
thing. And uh and it's just uh a dynamic
that maybe I wouldn't have designed, but
it's what I work in. It's uh it's it's
what, you know, I got to swim in the
waters that I'm in. I I can't swim in
other waters. I wouldn't design what's
going on in college football, but that's
what they work in and that's what we
have to adapt to. And so we adapt to the
environment we're in. And uh yes, I I
don't like seeing good players leave.
that doesn't help us. But the reality is
you can't keep everybody. It's just the
way that it is. But when you can keep T
and you can keep Jamar and you can keep
Joe and you know we have you know the
rest you know uh may maybe uh Chase
Brown who's emerged maybe he's a guy we
could keep or DJ or Dax or Jordan Battle
you we all these things. Can you keep
them all? I hope that's the goal. That's
the goal, but the reality we live in is
a little different than that.
>> How do you see this draft shaping up?
Strengths, weaknesses. I mean, [snorts]
>> um, we're just diving into it. The
juniors haven't even all fully declared
yet. Um, uh, the way college football is
now, the, uh, the the universe is is
hard to pin down.
You have your seniors, your juniors, uh,
you have sixth year guys. Uh we have a
lot of 24 and 24 5 year old guys. And
then you have the guys that declare
late. I think there's still a game
tonight and a game next weekend. And so
those players have their own uh
declaration dates uh where they'll say
they're coming in. So until all the
juniors really declare what they're
going to do, are they going to go back?
Are they going to transfer? Are they
going to be in the draft? It's hard to
really understand the full universe.
on defense. What's the number of new or
potential new starters that you want to
have on defense coming on from the
outside from outside free agency or the
draft?
>> Yeah. Um
I don't know that I can give an exact
number without giving away any plans.
You know, we hope to develop some
starters from within. uh you know that
I'm not eliminating anybody that's on
our current team in in developing cuz
that happens and uh and I'm I'm very
hopeful that it that it happens
>> this
>> but we have a number of we have a number
of positions that are going to be up.
We're going to increase the competition
on this team, you know, in every way we
can. Um, and we're going to bring in
guys and and guys from within this team,
you know, it might even be practice
squad players, you know, that are
ressigned now, but we're going to
increase the competition on this team
because we have to.
>> This specific this specific news
conference at the end of the season for
you has not been a typical thing in the
past, but you came out here with a
notepad. We've gone almost an hour now.
Why did
>> Has it been an hour?
>> Not quite. We're not
>> Why did you feel it was important to sit
in here and address us and the fans in
this way?
>> It was important for me to talk to the
fans. I I recognize it was important for
you guys to to get the opportunity.
Normally I do this in Mobile and uh some
of you show up and some of you don't.
And and uh I guess uh uh I've come
around. I can change and uh and if this
is something that you guys feel is
important, I'm I'm happy to uh to do
that. It's uh during the season, you
know, Zach is our voice and uh Zach is
somebody that uh speaks for us. We
communicate all the time with him and
and he understands everything that's
going on and he is the voice of our
team. And during the season, it's it's
about the players and it's about the
coaching staff and that's what it's
about. And so he is the guy that you'll
hear from during the season period. Uh
some organizations run that way, some do
it differently, but we believe in his
message and uh and his message is our
message during the season.
>> Duke, assuming that Trey is not back,
how imperative is it to try to add an
elite pass rusher? Um, yeah, I'm for
pass rush. I'm for pass rush. Um, I
don't know what the future holds for for
Trey. Those are those are discussions
that we're going to have to have
ongoing. You know, he's he's one of a
number of free agents that we have that
we'll have to decide uh how we're going
to go forward with. Um, but pass rush is
king and and you always need to be
layering in pass rusher. um it can
develop from within your team and I
think we've seen some of that start to
develop from within our team and then I
think we need to find some from external
sources as well.
>> Going back to your
>> That's going to be the last question.
>> Okay.
>> Going back to your first conversation
with Al last year through playing two
rookie linebackers next to each other
most of the year. What in your mind went
wrong in the linebacker room? And do you
feel like there was misalignment with
understanding what Al needed that maybe
you have a better plan [snorts] for the
second season? Um, I think I'm always
getting clarity from, you know, what
we're trying to do with our coaches, but
they, you know, we we meet before we go
and and linebacker was a need for us and
and to be quite honest, what we saw in
our young guys, they were starting to
eat into the playing time of of the
veterans we had and uh and Al had a lot
of confidence in those young guys. the
the growing pains that we saw this year
are going to pay off because we saw them
this year. It's not always fun while
they're happening. Uh but th those two
linebackers that that when they first
started playing to when they finished
the season at versus Cleveland out here
are night and day and you can see
exactly
uh what the vision is for those two
guys. And um yeah, we're always talking
to Al on what he wants to be. The great
thing about Al is he can be a lot of
different things based on what he has.
You know, that's what the best coaches
do. That's what he did at Notre Dame.
Here's what I have. So, here's what I'm
going to do to maximize what I have. And
then here's what I'd like to be. And
it's our job to try to build towards
that vision.
>> Thanks, Duke.
>> Yep. Thanks, guys.
>> [clears throat]